films.com 2012-11-29

# Films for the Humanities and Sciences - Privacy Policy

**FILMS MEDIA GROUP PRIVACY POLICY**

Films Media Group is strongly committed to protecting your privacy and providing a safe online experience for all of our users while offering the highest quality educational media to them. Because we gather certain types of information about and from users so that we can fulfill your requests and better serve your needs, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of this information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, how to correct or change it, and what steps we take to safeguard personal information provided to us both online and offline. Please read the complete Online Privacy Policy below, as well as our Terms and Conditions of Use, and contact us if you have any questions. 

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?**

You can visit our website without giving us any personally identifiable information. So that we can provide our users with the most efficient, enhanced, and personalized service, we request information about you in certain circumstances, and also collect certain information automatically. We also use contact lists and other information we may obtain from third parties. For the convenience of our customers and to better serve you, a customer account includes all the collected personal information we may have, but you can update or correct your contact information or change your preferences about receiving offers and information from us at any time. 

**_Information Users Volunteer_**

We collect personally identifiable information such as names, mailing addresses, and/or email addresses when you place an order (see the section below for more information on orders), or through optional, voluntary registration at our website. Website visitors may register to receive email updates, offers, catalogs or promotions. Registration may also be requested in connection with certain surveys. Registration can be accomplished by submitting your email address, name, address, phone number and institution. Our registration form will indicate what information is required and what information (if any) is optional. This information will be collected during registration on our site or in connection with specific activities (for example, when placing an order). 

**_Orders_**

If you wish to place an order online, you must either establish a credit card account with us or go through a purchase order approval process. In addition to the customary information needed to fill your order (full name, address, ship-to name and address), orders necessitate collection of additional personal information, such as your credit card number and credit card expiration date, or your purchase order number. 

**_Information Collected Automatically_**

We also may collect your IP address, browser type, access times and referring website address. This helps facilitate your online experience at our website. In addition, we may use cookies to track usage patterns at our site. See below for more detail on cookies. 

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH COLLECTED INFORMATION?**

**_We use information you provide to fulfill your requests and improve our products._**

We use personal information so that we may display or send custom, personalized content to our website visitors and to send newsletters, mail, emails, features, promotional material, surveys and other updates, information or offers to our users. A user may, at any time, opt out of receiving such information. We also use collected information to evaluate and administer our products and services, fulfill customer requests, respond to any problems that may arise (such as delivery issues, difficulties in navigating our site or accessing certain features), as well as to gauge user trends to determine what products and services are most popular with users. 

Of course, we use personal information to allow you to make product purchases at our website. Rest assured that we and our technical and fulfillment agents and consultants follow careful procedures to safeguard credit card data in connection with your transactions. 

**HOW DO WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Personal information is available to Films Media Group and its technical and fulfillment agents and consultants who make this site and our products and services available to you. We share your personal information with third parties only with your prior permission. 

**_Films Media Group and Its Agents_**

Films Media Group may access any personal information you provide for internal marketing purposes, including sending you notice of new publications, services or products we offer likely to be of interest, and filling orders. To facilitate orders, Films Media Group will cache your order information, and create an authorization with a merchant account (i.e., your credit card company) if you use a credit card to make a purchase. There are many companies who may be required to assist Films Media Group in making its products and website available to you. Web host firms and technical and database consultants may have access to personally identifiable information in the course of making our products and services available. All companies working for Films Media Group must comply with our information collection, use and disclosure policies, and are not permitted to sell your information to third parties or to use it except as authorized by us and you, or as permitted or required by law. 

**_Credit Card Companies_**

As in any transaction, your credit card company will receive relevant information about the item(s) purchased, your name, and your billing address. Films Media Group will not otherwise provide any personal data to your credit card company. 

**_Important Note_**

We reserve the right to use or disclose any information without notice or consent as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request; to conduct investigations of consumer complaints or possible breaches of law; to protect the integrity of our site and our property; to protect the safety of our visitors or others; to fulfill your requests; or to cooperate in any legal investigation. 

**HOW DO WE USE COOKIES?**

Your Web browser offers so-called “cookies” which, if you allow their use, store small amounts of data on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information about you and therefore cannot be used to identify you personally. Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features you like best. Cookies also enable us to customize our content according to your preferences. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying your browser and our websites are viewable even if you disable the cookie function on your browser. However, if you disable cookies, some features or offerings will not be available to you. For example, disabling cookies will prevent you from making purchases since our website shopping cart is cookie-based. 

**HOW CAN YOU CONTROL YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We believe that choice in how and when you are contacted is key to customer satisfaction, so we offer several ways for you to update your contact information or change your preferences. 

  1. If you are a registered user at our website, you will be able to log in and update or change your contact or account information.
  2. You may unsubscribe to any of our online email updates by following the unsubscribe instructions in the body of any message.
  3. You may write to us and update your contact information or ask that we not share your personal contact information with third parties at: Films Media Group, c/o Privacy Coordinator, 132 West 31st Street 17th Floor New York, NY 10001. In those instances, we will retain your information in a “do not promote” file in our database.
  4. You may also contact us at [privacypolicy@filmsmediagroup.com](mailto:privacypolicy@filmsmediagroup.com).

We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive promotional information from us by mail for up to 60 days due to printing and mailing schedules, and up to 10 days for email. 

**SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt important information, such as your credit card data, in an effort to prevent unauthorized access during transmission of your orders over the Internet. We incorporate standard industry practices internally and with our service providers suitable to the degree of sensitivity of the information involved to maintain the security of your personal information and to avoid its disclosure except as described in this policy. 

Your personal information will also be protected by the password you created when you registered at our website. The confidentiality of any password is yours to protect. You may change it anytime by following the instructions on the website. Although we use our best efforts to assure that your data remains secure when maintained by us, security during Internet transmissions cannot be assured. Films Media Group employees are made aware of its privacy practices through periodic communications and training. We limit access to personal data only to those Films Media Group employees or agents with a specific need to access or retrieve this information. We store data on multiple service systems, in controlled, secure environments. To maintain the highest level of security, we conduct internal reviews of our security measures on a regular basis. 

**LINKS**

Films Media Group may offer links to or from websites it controls to other sites within the Films Media Group family as well as to sites operated by third parties. We offer links to third party sites so that you can conveniently visit our partners or locate other content likely to be of interest. We are not responsible for the content, practices or policies of sites operated by third parties and urge you to inquire about them before providing any personally identifiable information. 

**CHANGES IN CORPORATE STRUCTURE**

In developing our business, we might sell certain assets, or the company, or parts of it, may be sold, merged or otherwise transferred. In such transactions, user information, whether personally identifiable or otherwise, may be one of the transferred assets. 

**VISITORS AND SUBSCRIBERS OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES**

Our websites and the servers that make these sites available worldwide are located in the United States. All matters relating to these sites are governed by the laws of the State of New York in the United States. Any information you provide in registering or ordering at our website will be transferred to the United States. By visiting our sites and submitting information you authorize this transfer, processing and use. 

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy as necessary to protect our users and to comply with a changing environment. We recommend that you check the policy when you visit our site to be sure you are aware of and understand our current policy. If we make material changes to this policy or in how we will use or collect your personally identifiable information, we will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. We will not make material changes in how we handle previously collected personal information that have retroactive effect unless legally required to do so, and we will email registered website visitors information on material changes to this policy. 

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please email us at [privacypolicy@filmsmediagroup.com](mailto:privacypolicy@filmsmediagroup.com). Please include the URL of the Web site and/or name of the publication involved in your request. 

Or you can contact us by mail at: 

Privacy Coordinator   
Films Media Group  
132 West 31st Street  
17th Floor  
New York, NY 10001

Or you can fax us at: 609-671-0266, Attn: Privacy Coordinator 

_Updated: May 19, 2006_
